Contact

vvvgkrishna@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ gopalvemulapalli (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Azure API Management
ASP.NET Razor

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Telugu (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Elementary)

Gopal Vemulapalli

Sr .Net Developer | SC cleared

Cheltenham, England, United Kingdom

Summary

18+ years of experience in design, develop and maintaining complex applications using Microsoft technologies specifically Web APIs, ASP.Net MVC, Blazor and Web forms, C#, SQL Server

Rich experience in client side technologies like Java Script/Type Script, Angular/AngularJS,React, JQuery, Knockout JS, CSS, HTML5.

API integration experience with Elasticsearch , MMS, MS NAV, SharePoint

Experienced in Agile methodologies, Continuous Integration and TDD

SC cleared Microsoft certified professional

Experience

Landmarc Support Services Limited
.Net Developer
September 2014 - Present (10 years 10 months)
Tilshead, Salisbury

In my role as a .Net Developer at Landmarc Support Services Limited, my key responsibilities include

- Create web apps and RESTful APIs for a Microservice architecture based solution
- Design, build, maintain various web applications build with MS technologies like C#, ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework
- Create Single Page Applications (SPA) with Angular and React
- Design, build and develop RESTful APIs
- Create and schedule console apps for long running jobs
- · Integrations with on-premise MS NAV and Business central in Azure
- Integration with ASIte in Azure for documents

- Integrations with on-premise Sharepoint
- Install and configure Elasticsearch in a cluster environment
- Create SOAP service for data exchange with DIO IMS
- Create and publish Nuget packages to internal Nuger server
- Create and publish npm packages to internal Verdassio NPM server
- Create and configure Elasticsearch cluster for high availability
- CI/CD pipelines for on-prem and Azure DevOps environments
- Create Powershell scripts for data restore to test environments
- Deploy web applications and APIs to Azure App services
- Using Graph API, send email notification from applications hosted in Azure
- Create Azure function app to monitor to notify expiring client secrets
- Set up test and production environments
- Code reviews and mentoring
- · Sprint planning and retro meetings
- Document software development methodologies in technical manuals to be used by IT personnel in future projects

Environment Agency
.Net Consultant
June 2008 - August 2014 (6 years 3 months)

Accenture India Team Lead October 2006 - March 2008 (1 year 6 months) Hyderabad, India

Mahindra Satyam (formerly Satyam Comupters Service Limited) Sr Software Engineer 2005 - 2006 (1 year)

Olive Technology Analyst Programmer 2004 - 2005 (1 year) Hyderabad, India

Education

Osmania University
Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)